

Shrihari Sankaran

Output London, United Kingdom

I'm a product designer and developer who believes in creating simple, beautiful and meaningful experiences

http://shrihari.me/portfolio.pdf

shrihari@hey.com

+44 7846 181849

Experience

Product Designer / Senior Product Designer - BridgeU

London, July 2018 - Present

http://bridge-u.com

- Joined as the first designer. Integral to team expansion, actively participated in growing the design team from 1 to 7 members. Coached and mentored junior designers, helping them progress in their design careers.
- Worked on a diverse range of projects from minor improvements to comprehensive overhauls. Owned the full design process from user research to ideation to visual design
- Primarily responsible for user engagement of both student and advisor users. Improved user engagement through a variety of projects
- Led the establishment of the first component library and design system, which powers around 90% of the designs today
- Promoted to Senior in 2020. Company acquired by Kaplan International in 2020

Product Designer - Freshworks

Chennai, February 2015 - June 2018

http://freshworks.com

- Designed their SaaS call-center product Freshcaller. A zero-to-one project. Working as the sole designer, took the product from concept to MVP to launch.
- The product is part of a suite of products by Freshworks, and is used by over 60000 customers today.

UX Design Intern - Zoomcar

Bangalore, May - September 2014

http://zoomcar.com

Frontend Developer - Tenmiles

Chennai, 2010 - 2011

http://tenmiles.com

Education

Design for Digital Experience - Master of Design

National Institute of Design, 2012 - 2015

Computer Science - Bachelor of Technology

SASTRA University, 2008 - 2012

Skills	Tools	Tech
User research	Pen & Paper	HTML, CSS
UI & UX design	Figma & Figjam	Javascript
Wireframing	Sketch	React, React Native
Prototyping	Condens	Node.js
User testing		Git

Background

Hey 👋 I'm **Shri**, a product designer + frontend developer based in London, UK.

I got into tech & design when I was 15, building simple websites on Geocities over dial-up internet. These days, I spend most of my time designing simple & usable experiences for digital products. I design in Figma and build in HTML, CSS and Javascript.

I'm a generalist designer working all the way from user research to UI design and even stretching into frontend development. While I've worked primarily in "product design" roles, I identify as a "maker". I have a deep understanding of HTML, CSS and Javascript and enjoy writing code as much as designing things.

When not working, I enjoy writing, playing the guitar, learning French and going on hikes.